Finding Aid for Leonard Bernard Willeke papers, 1900-1984
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Leonard Bernard Willeke papers 1900-1984, 1906-1958
Willeke, Leonard Bernard, 1884-1970.
54 oversize folders
26 tubes
9.5 linear feet (in 11 boxes)
9632 Aa 2
Cincinnati and Detroit based architect. Major commissions include the Grosse Pointe Shores, Michigan residence for Oscar Webber, the Fordson Village Development, and the Goulburn Avenue and Dresden Avenue Defense Houses in Detroit. The collection consists primarily of project files, correspondence, personal diaries, photographs, commission accounts, and architectural drawings.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was obtained in two accessions. The bulk of the collection came from Thomas Brunk (donor no. 8193 ) in 2009. A smaller accession had previously been received from the University of Michigan Art and Architecture Library (donor no. 8439 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Leonard B. Willeke was born 1884 in Cincinnati, Ohio. His architectural career began in his hometown where he worked as a draftsman for the architectural firm of Rudolph Tietig & Walter H. Lee. He left Cincinnati in December of 1905 for a brief stint in New York City. While living in New York, Willeke enrolled in a special program at Columbia University on the history of architecture and ornamentation. Besides studying at Columbia University, Willeke also took a job with Trowbridge & Livingston. His first assignment was to design the store fixtures for the B. Altman and Company building on Fifth Avenue. In the spring of 1906, Willeke traveled west to San Francisco with Trowbridge & Livingston after the firm had been selected to rebuild the Palace Hotel, which had been destroyed in the earthquake. For this eight million dollar commission, Willeke helped design the Great Palm Court, the main grillroom and bar, the main corridor, the state apartments, the main iron balcony, and the marquee and carriage entrance, among others.
With the new Palace Hotel completed, Willeke decided not to return to New York but to stay in California and work for the San Francisco firm of George C. Sellon and E. Charles Hemming and later for the California Architectural Department in Sacramento. During his time in California, Willeke designed buildings for the State Hospital at Agnew, the State Normal School at San Jose and San Diego, and Folsom Prison.
By September of 1908, Willeke decided to leave California in favor of studying architecture abroad. Willeke moved into a pension in Paris' Latin Quarter and started working in the atelier of Stanislas-Louis Bernier. By spring of 1909, however, Willeke became frustrated by his atelier work in Paris and decided to tour Europe. When he ended his European adventures in the fall of 1910, Willeke had traveled throughout France, Spain, Italy, Germany and England. He returned to Cincinnati with 8,000 postcards, 27 bound albums of photos, daily journals, and multiple sketchbooks.
After a few years working in different architectural firms in Cincinnati and briefly partnering with Detroit architect Elmore Ray Dunlap, Willeke started his own practice in the late spring of 1917. Some of his earliest private practice work was for Henry Ford's Fair Lane estate, where he designed and built a rustic, log skating house and a group of service buildings.
Throughout the 1920s, Willeke was known for designing fine residential work for wealthy clients. His work includes some of the most beautiful mansions in Grosse Pointe Park, Michigan. Among his larger residential work includes commissions for a grand residence for Oscar Webber, the vice president of J.L. Hudson Company, an English inspired manor for William A. Petzold, secretary and treasurer of J.L. Hudson Company, and a Tudor-style mansion for Raymond J. Purdy, an auto accessories and windshield manufacturer.
During the Depression, fine residential work came to a halt. After a few years of struggling to find work, Willeke decided to try his hand at designing defense housing. Viewing the rising demand for working class housing in Detroit because of World War II as an opportunity, Willeke began to build houses for resale. One project included building forty-seven single-family houses on Dresden Street in Detroit. Willeke's ability to adapt his architectural talent for designing artistically detailed mansions into an eye for building functional, low-income housing helped him financially recover from the Depression.
Leonard Willeke died on July 2, 1970.
The Willeke papers are organized into three series: Personal Papers, Professional Papers, and Defense Housing. The collection encompasses eleven linear feet of correspondence, photographs, journals, sketches, commission notebooks and accounts, as well as architectural drawings in eight flat file drawers, and twenty-four tubes.
Subjects:
Willeke, Leonard Bernard, 1884-1970.; Architects--Michigan.; Architectural drawings (visual works)--Michigan.; Architectural drawings (visual works)--Ohio--Cincinnati.; Architecture--Michigan.; Architecture--Designs and plans.; Dwellings--Michigan.; Ford, Edsel, 1893-1943--Homes and haunts.; Public housing--California.; Public housing--Michigan.; Skyscrapers.; Webber, Oscar--Homes and haunts.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Willeke, Leonard Bernard, 1884-1970.; Camping--California.; Dwellings--Michigan--Detroit.; Detroit (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Fountains--Michigan--Detroit.; Ford, Edsel, 1893-1943--Homes and haunts.
Genre Terms:
Architectural drawings.; Diaries.; Drawings (visual works); Photographs.
- Personal Papers
  The series Personal Papers contains correspondence to and from Willeke from 1909 to 1958 as well as personal photographs of family and friends, and other material collected by Willeke throughout his life. The series contains a significant collection of material related to Willeke's two years in Europe during 1908 through 1910. Material related to Willeke's European travels includes correspondence, photographs, collected memorabilia, and eleven personal diaries.
  - Correspondence
    - Atkinson, E. 1910 (Box 1)
    - Baruffi, Marqurite and Andre 1909-1910 (Box 1)
    - Blodgett, Laurence and Henrietta 1948-1958 (Box 1)
    - Boggess, Dr. John S. 1927-1934 (Box 1)
    - Brittan, Harold circa 1909 (Box 1)
    - Collier, Dr. Leon B. 1929 (Box 1)
    - de Mari, Walter 1909-1910 (Box 1)
    - Fassett, Francis Henry 1909-1910, 1917-1948 (Box 1)
    - Fee, William T. 1908-1956, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Johannigman, John and Etta 1908-1944 (Box 1)
    - Levy, Emilio 1909 (Box 1)
    - Lott, Louis J.P. 1933-1937 (Box 1)
    - Meiners, Elizabeth Burdick 1921-1948 (Box 1)
    - Meiners, Harry F. 1956-1958 (Box 1)
    - Meiners, Raymond J. 1928-1956 (Box 1)
    - Montillier, A. 1909 (Box 1)
    - Murphy, F.V. 1909 (Box 1)
    - Schreiner, Max 1910-1911 (Box 1)
    - Soldwedel, Frederick A. 1909-1910 (Box 1)
    - Vibbert, Charles Bruce 1909 (Box 1)
    - Wagner, W. Sydney 1909-1921 (Box 1)
    - Watts, Wintter 1909 (Box 1)
    - Weirick, Ralph 1909-1910 (Box 1)
    - Willeke, August Prieshoff 1956 (Box 1)
    - Willeke, Edith 1909 (Box 1)
    - Willeke, Joe 1916 (Box 1)
    - Willeke, Leonard B., Jr. 1940-1947 (Box 1)
    - Willeke, William Anthony 1922-1923 (Box 1)
    - Zettel, John 1909 (Box 1)
  - Income tax returns 1918-1931 (Box 1)
  - Lochmoor Club 1924-1939 (Box 1)
    (includes a portrait of Willeke)
  - Other Memberships 1904-1929 (Box 1)
  - Registration Certificates and Identification Cards 1910s-1960s (Box 1)
  - Funeral Program 1970 (Box 1)
  - Notebooks
    - "Sketch of Trip from Cincinnati to Washington, D.C. via C&O," 1905 (Box 1)
    - "Notes of Interest in New York City, NY," 1905-1908 (Box 1)
    - "Billete por Kilometros," 1909 (Box 1)
    - Personal Account Book 1910 (Box 1)
  - European Trip
    - Miscellaneous papers, letters, and memorabilia 1908-1910 (Box 1)
    - Pencil Drawings and Sketches 1908-1910 (Box 1)
    - Notebook containing pencil drawings undated (Box 1)
    - Diaries
      - September 05-06, 1908 30 March 1909-20 May 1909 (Box 1)
      - March 1909 (Box 1)
      - Seville to Caserta May-July 9, 1909 (Box 1)
      - Italian Trip Notes June 1909 (Box 1)
      - Rome to Sienna, Prato to Vicenza September-December, 1909 (Box 1)
      - Paris to Stratford-upon-Avon April-June 1910 (Box 1)
      - Stratford-upon-Avon to Horsham April-June 1910 (Box 1)
      - Horsham to The Hague July 1910 (Box 1)
      - The Hague to Mänlichen Peak, Switzerland July-September 1910 (Box 1)
      - Sailing notes, general notes, and addresses April-September 1910 (Box 1)
      - January-September 1910 (Box 1)
  - Photographs and Negatives
    - Miscellaneous Travel undated (Box 1)
    - Unidentified Trip circa 1910s (Box 1)
    - California Camping Trip circa 1906, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - California Camping Trip and San Francisco Coast circa 1906 (Box 1)
    - Western Landscape circa 1906, 8 folders (Box 2)
    - Yosemite and Hetch Hetchy circa 1906 (Box 2)
    - European Trip, miscellaneous enlarged prints 1909-1910, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Alhambra and Seville 1909 (Box 2)
      (includes photograph of Rene Binet)
    - Paris, Naples, Sicily, Pompeii, Palermo 1909 (Box 2)
    - Pyrenees Mountains circa 1910 (Box 2)
    - Tunisia, North Africa circa 1910 (Box 2)
    - Kentucky Hills undated (Box 2)
    - Family and Friends 1900-1950, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Early Family Vacations 1910s-1920s, 6 folders (Box 2)
    - Family Photographs (Leonard, Lee, LBW, Jr.)
      - 1915-1918, 5 folders (Box 2)
      - 1920s-1950s, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Residences in Cincinnati and Detroit circa 1910s (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous Houses undated (Box 2)
      (Willeke's note: "Not my work, but good example for reference")
    - Portrait of Leona Willeke circa 1910s (Box 10)
- Professional Papers
  The series Professional Papers covers Willeke's architectural career from his earliest architectural work with the Cincinnati firm of Rudolph Tietig & Walter H. Lee to his later work under his own Detroit based practice. The series is made up of two subseries: General and Commissions.
  - General
    The General subseries consists of material related to Willeke's career as an architect but not necessarily stemming from his actual architectural commissions, such as Willeke's collection of architectural book catalogues and other architectural publications. The material has been arranged alphabetically.
    - Account Notebook #1 (Box 2)
      (W. Clay, R.B. Jackson, H. Ford, E. Ford, D.S. Arts and Crafts furniture, C. Sorenson, W. Petzold)
    - Account Notebook #2 1921-1923 (Box 3)
      (Grewell House, George Quigley, C.H. Crockett, Dr. Vaughan, E. Huber, G. Zimmerman, J. Vincent, J. Van Loon)
    - Allyn Engineering Company Meeting Minutes 1913 (Box 3)
    - American Institute of Architects (AIA), Standard Documents 1912-1961 (Box 3)
    - Application for Registration 1915 (Box 3)
      (photocopy)
    - Architectural Album Library Catalogue 1953, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Architectural Book Catalogue
      - Italian 1896-1907 (Box 3)
      - French 1906-1909 (Box 3)
      - German 1910 (Box 3)
      - English 1910 (Box 3)
      - British Museum 1909 (Box 3)
      - William Helburn 1919-1921 (Box 3)
      - B.T. Batsford 1909 (Box 3)
      - American 1912-1948, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Architectural Library Inventory 1958 (Box 3)
    - Architectural Office, stationary and material undated (Box 3)
    - Beaux Arts Project photographs of drawings, undated (Box 10)
    - Beaux Arts Projects, watercolor and pen rendering and original pencil on tracing paper sketches undated (Box 10)
    - California State Architects Office, Blueprint Cartoons 1909 (Box 10)
    - Cincinnati Architectural Club and Cincinnati Chapter of American Institute of Architects 1900s-1910s (Box 3)
    - Cincinnati Art Academy Catalogue 1904-1905 (Box 3)
    - Cincinnati Illustrated, a pictorial guide to Cincinnati and the Suburbs, 1880 (Box 3)
    - Comparative Cost Data 1925 (Box 3)
    - Conceptual Sketch of Cottage, original pencil drawing undated (Box 10)
    - Correspondence
      - Career outlines and resumes 1914-1942, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Hemmings, Edward Charles 1909-1910 (Box 3)
      - Letters of Recommendation 1905 (Box 3)
      - Michigan Board of Examiners for Registration of Architects 1916-1930 (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous (landscape architects, surveyors) 1924-1954 (Box 3)
      - Winkworth, F. Bruce 1940-1949 (Box 3)
        (about landscape design and contracting)
    - Drawing Inventory Notebook 1927-1928 (Box 3)
      (Commission #219-222)
    - English Tudor Style Notes undated (Box 3)
    - Grosse Pointe Public Library Bookplate, proposed 1934 (Box 3)
    - L.B.W., INC.
      - Income Tax Returns 1943-1956, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Legal Papers and Correspondence 1942-1957, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Michigan Annual Reports 1943-1957 (Box 3)
    - Mantel Ornamentation Photographs, undated (Box 3)
    - Membership Certificates, AIA and Michigan Society of Architects 1944, 1955 (Box 3)
    - Mendenhall's Standard Guide Map of Cincinnati 1912 (Box 3)
    - Michigan Society of Architects, Bulletin and registration certificate 1933, 1948 (Box 3)
    - Paris Salon Exhibition, submission tag 1912 (Box 3)
    - Project Ledger under Sellon and Hemmings 1907-1908 (Box 3)
    - Receipts
      - Furniture 1912-1927 (Box 4)
      - Manning Brothers Commercial Photographers 1919-1920 (Box 4)
      - Publications 1911-1971 (Box 4)
    - Templates
      - Building Agreement undated (Box 4)
      - General Conditions of the Contract undated (Box 4)
      - Lien Law Waiver 1929 (Box 4)
    - Tietig and Lee Book undated (Box 4)
    - Unidentified Residences Photographs, undated (Box 4)
      (probably not Willeke's work)
    - Weekly Time Book 1907-1908 (Box 4)
    - Willeke Exhibit, Detroit Historical Society 1984 (Box 4)
  - Commissions
    The subseries Commissions is made up of Willeke's project files. The subseries contains two sub-subseries: By Date and Undated. The project files under sub-subseries By Date have been arranged chronologically under their project name. The project files under sub-subseries Undated have been arranged alphabetically. When available, the commission number assigned by Willeke has been provided in a parenthetical note. The subseries contains paper records supplemented with architectural drawings and sketches. The paper records include correspondence, photographs, specifications, and project notebooks and accounts. The majority of architectural drawings are original pencil on tracing paper, though there are many blueprints and original ink drawings as well. The architectural drawings range from formal floor or elevation plans and mounted renderings to quick detail sketches or conceptual drawings. It is important to note that since many of the commissions contain both paper records and architectural drawings, single projects may be housed in multiple locations, whether in a box, tube, or flat-file drawer. For example, the paper records of Henry C. Bogle Residence are located in Box 6, while the project's architectural drawings are located in tube 4 as well as drawer 4, folder 25. As a result, it is important to carefully note the location of the material.
    - By Date
      - John G. Johanningman Residence, Architectural Drawings, 481 Riddle Road, Cincinnati 1905 (Map-case 1, Folder 1)
        (original ink drawings)
      - Rudolph Tietig Residence Photographs, 3333 Stettinius Avenue, Cincinnati, 1905 (Box 4)
      - Baby Palace Hotel, northwest corner of Post and Leavenworth, San Francisco 1906 (Box 4)
      - Palace Hotel, Photographs, Market at New Montgomery Streets, San Francisco 1906, 3 folders (Box 4)
        (includes photograph of Willeke's façade rendering)
      - Union-Pacific Design Competition, San Francisco 1907 (Box 4)
      - Sacramento Hotel, 10th at K Streets, Sacramento 1907 (Box 4)
      - Agnew State Hospital, Agnew, California
        - Photographs, 1907-1908, 2 folders (Box 4)
        - Correspondence with Dr. Leonard Stocking 1907-1908 (Box 4)
        - Architectural drawing 1907 (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
          (copy of original drawing)
      - California State building, Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition, Seattle 1908 (Box 4)
      - California State Insectary for Capitol Park, Sacramento
        - Photograph, circa 1908 (Box 4)
        - Architectural Drawing 1907 (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
      - San Jose Normal School
        - Architectural Drawing 1907 (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
        - Photographs, 1908 (Box 4)
        - Correspondence 1912 (Box 4)
      - Mary Johannigman Residence, 489 Riddle Road, Cincinnati
        - Photograph, 1908 (Box 4)
        - Architectural Drawings 1908 (Box 10)
          (blueprints)
      - Drusilla Flats, 3529 Middleton Avenue, Cincinnati 1911 (Box 4)
        (photocopied image)
      - Hansleman Masonic Lodge, No. 208 F. & A.M., Cincinnati 1911 (Box 4)
      - Chamber of Commerce Building, Cincinnati 1911 (Box 4)
      - New Gibson House, Fourth at Walnut Streets, Cincinnati 1911 (Box 4)
      - Chamber of Commerce and Business Men's Club, Cincinnati 1911 (Box 4)
      - Cincinnati Tuberculosis Hospital, Lick Run, Cincinnati 1911 (Box 4)
      - Perry Memorial Competition, Put-in-Bay, Ohio 1911 (Box 4)
      - Union Central Life Building Competition, Insurance Company Building, Architectural Drawings 1911 (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
        (pencil rendering on tracing paper)
      - Rosa Rendigs Residence, 2583 Observatory Road, Cincinnati 1911 (Box 4)
      - Edward W. Edwards Residence, 2567 Observatory Road 1911 (Box 4)
      - Henry S. Irving Residence, 1865 Madison Road, Cincinnati 1911 (Box 4)
      - Fourteenth District School, 940 Poplar Street, Cincinnati 1911 (Box 4)
      - H. Sophie Newcomb Memorial College Competition, Tulane University, New Orleans 1911 (Box 4)
      - Engineering College Building, University of Cincinnati 1911 (Box 4)
      - Vernon C. Woods, Bronze Mausoleum 1912 (Box 4)
      - Temple K.K. Bene Israel, Cincinnati 1912 (Box 4)
      - Unidentified Building for Tietig and Lee 1912 (Box 4)
      - William Hayner Estate Mausoleum, Riverside Cemetery, Troy, Ohio 1912 (Box 4)
      - Garfield Place, Architectural Drawings, 8th Street between vine and Elm Streets, Cincinnati 1912 (Map-case 1, Folder 4)
      - Masonic Temple, Lexington, Kentucky 1912 (Box 4)
      - Peter Smith & Sons' Building, 1145 Griswold at State Street, Detroit 1912 (Box 4)
      - Republic Office building, Fifth at Walnut Street, Louisville, Kentucky 1912 (Box 4)
      - Western Implement and Motor Company 1912 (Box 4)
      - New Miami Hotel, Second Avenue at Ludlow Street, Dayton 1912 (Box 4)
      - Morris U. Bernheim Residence, 195 Green Hills Road, Cincinnati 1912 (Box 4)
      - Leonard's Reliable Storage Company Building, Detroit 1912 (Box 4)
      - Grand Park Hotel, East Adams at Witherell Street, Detroit 1912 (Box 4)
      - Dayton Bicycle Club Building, Dayton 1913 (Box 4)
      - Hamilton County Court House Competition Program, Cincinnati
        - Competition Programs 1913 (Box 4)
        - Architectural drawing undated (Map-case 1, Folder 5)
          (original pencil on tracing paper drawing)
      - Cadillac Hotel, Detroit 1913 (Box 4)
      - Bessie Thompson Residence, 300 Drury Lane, Troy, Ohio 1913 (Box 4)
      - Walter S. Kidder Residence, 46 North Arnold Place, Dayton 1913 (Box 4)
      - Mary Jane Hayner Residence and Garden, 301 West Main Street, Troy 1913, 2 folders (Box 4)
      - New Hotel Bushnell, Springfield, Ohio 1913 (Box 4)
      - Eloise Women's Hospital, Wayne County Poor Commission 1914-1917 (Box 4)
      - Howard Wurlitzer Residence, 6 Beech Crest Lane, Cincinnati 1914 (Box 4)
      - Alpena Hotel, Alpena, Michigan 1914 (Box 4)
      - Central Trust Building, Charleston, West Virginia 1914 (Box 4)
      - Apartment building, Bay City, Michigan 1914 (Box 4)
      - Unidentified building, rendering 1914 (Box 4)
      - Auditorium and Studio Building, Detroit 1914 (Box 4)
      - Frederick J. Flach Residence, 1 Beech Crest Lane 1915 (Box 4)
        (Tietig and Lee)
      - National Bank of Flint, Flint 1914 (Box 4)
      - Royal Oak Town Hall, Royal Oak, Michigan 1914 (Box 4)
      - Barbas Rooming House Proposal, Detroit 1914 (Box 4)
      - Community Apartment Group, Home Building Association of the Twentieth Century Club of Detroit 1914 (Box 4)
      - Burns Avenue German Baptist Church, 5481 Burns Avenue, Detroit 1915 (Box 4)
      - Hupp Motor Company, Building E, Milwaukee at Mt. Elliott Street, Detroit 1915 (Box 4)
      - Michigan Epileptic Farm Colony, Wahjamega, Michigan 1915 (Box 4)
      - Buckingham Hotel, Cass Avenue at Peterboro, Detroit 1915 (Box 4)
      - Stores and Apartment Building for Gustave A. Lindke, Monroe Street, Detroit 1915 (Box 4)
      - Beyers Memorial Hospital, Architectural drawings, Prospect Road, Ypsilanti 1916 (Tube 1)
      - Fay-Grainger Hotel 1916 (Box 4)
      - Edsel B. Ford Residence Alternations and Additions, Correspondence, 2171 Iroquois Avenue, Detroit 1917 (Box 4)
        (photocopies, not originals)
      - William Clay Residence, 2501 Iroquois Avenue, Photographs and Project Plan 1917
        (Commission #171)
        - Photographs and Project Plans 1917 (Box 4)
        - Architectural Drawings undated (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
          (blueprints and original pencil drawings)
      - Kanzler (Clay) Residence Furniture, Architectural Drawings, 2501 Iroquois Avenue, Detroit 1917 (Map-case 2, Folder 7)
      - Roscoe B. Jackson Residence, 2505 Iroquois Avenue, Detroit (Box 4)
        (Commission #172)
        - Paper Records 1917, 4 folders (Box 4)
        - Architectural Drawings undated (Map-case 2, Folder 8)
          (original pencil on tracing paper drawings)
      - Joseph T. Webber Residence, 2475 Iroquois Avenue, Detroit
        (Commission #177)
        - Paper Records 1917 (Box 4)
        - Architectural drawings undated (Map-case 2, Folder 9)
          (original ink and pencil drawings)
      - Sidney Corbett Hall Furniture, Architectural drawings 1917 (Map-case 2, Folder 10)
        (original pencil drawings)
      - 1919 Essex Phaeton Automobile, Essex Motor Company, Detroit, 1918 (Map-case 2, Folder 11)
      - Fordson Village Development, Dearborn
        - Village plan, aerial view undated (Tube 26)
        - Sketches of village plan, area maps, and project overview 1918 (Map-case 7, Folder 44)
        - Village houses and buildings blueprints 1918 (Map-case 7, Folder 45)
        - Housing floor plans 1918 (Map-case 7, Folder 46)
        - Housing sketches 1918 (Map-case 7, Folder 47)
          (includes one mounted rendering of main entrance building)
      - Leonard B. Willeke Residence, 39 Moss Street, Highland Park
        - Color pencil rendering on tracing paper undated (Box 5)
        - Correspondence with Louis Lott 1920 (Box 5)
        - Architectural drawings 1919 (Tube 1)
      - Speculative Residence, 2254 Longfellow Avenue, Detroit
        - Architectural Drawings 1919 (Tube 1)
        - Photographs undated (Box 5)
      - Charles E. Sorenson Residence, Architectural Drawings, Warren Road, Detroit 1919 (Map-case 2, Folder 12)
      - Edsel B. Ford Residence, Alternations, 7930 East Jefferson Avenue, Detroit
        - Paper Records 1919 (Box 5)
        - Architectural Drawings undated (Map-case 7, Folder 48)
      - Raymond J. Meiners Two-family House, Architectural Drawings, Detroit 1920 (Tube 1)
        (Commission #186)
      - George E. Quigley Residence, 1990 Longfellow Avenue, Detroit
        (Commission #188)
        - Mounted Rendering 1921 (Box 10)
        - Specifications 1921 (Box 5)
      - Speculative Residence, 2425 Longfellow Avenue, Detroit 1921 (Box 5)
        (Commission #189)